<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
	<generator uri="https://dieghernan.github.io/chulapa" version="1.0.0">Chulapa</generator>
	<link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
	<link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
	<updated>2024-08-04T12:48:18-04:00</updated>
	<id>http://localhost:4000/atom.xml</id>
	<title>Justin Lanjil | Artist & Storyteller</title>
	<subtitle>Artist & Storyteller</subtitle>
	<author>
		<name>Justin</name>
					
	</author>
	<rights>(c) 2024, Justin</rights>
	<icon>http://localhost:4000/assets/img/brand_img/brand_logo_social_60x60.png</icon>
	<logo>http://localhost:4000/assets/img/brand_img/brand_logo_social_60x60.png</logo><entry>
		<title>Godot 4.3 fixes web export, yay!
</title>
		<link href="http://localhost:4000/20240804_godot-web-export/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Godot 4.3 fixes web export, yay!
"/>
		<published>2024-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</published>
		<updated>2024-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://localhost:4000/20240804_godot-web-export/</id>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/20240804_godot-web-export/">
		
  		
	&lt;p&gt;1 min.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;I downloaded &lt;a href=&quot;https://godotengine.org/article/release-candidate-godot-4-3-rc-2/&quot;&gt;Godot 4.3 Release Candidate 2&lt;/a&gt; to see if Web Export is fixed and…it is! Going to import my &lt;a href=&quot;/games/20-games-challenge&quot;&gt;20 games challenge games&lt;/a&gt; into 4.3, fix them up, and add them to their respective pages. Flappy Bat is up, Pong needs a bit of work from design bugginess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m mostly motivated to post it because of Breakout tbh. I might end up being a little half-assed with a few of the upcoming challenges and not upload them, but we’ll see how it goes. I also might spice up the gameplay pages as well to add some custom styling…depending on how much work I want to put in.&lt;/p&gt;

		</content>
		
		<author>
			<name>Justin</name></author>
		<summary type="html">Godot 4.3 finally fixed web export, so now I can actually post my games from the 20 game challenge.</summary>
		<category term="posts"/>
		<category term="game makin"/>
	</entry><entry>
		<title>Setting up 1:7 scale figure sculpt
</title>
		<link href="http://localhost:4000/20240512_1-7-scale-sculpt/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Setting up 1:7 scale figure sculpt
"/>
		<published>2024-05-12T00:00:00-04:00</published>
		<updated>2024-05-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://localhost:4000/20240512_1-7-scale-sculpt/</id>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/20240512_1-7-scale-sculpt/">
		
  		
	&lt;p&gt;3 min.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;With my &lt;a href=&quot;20240402_sculpting-rough-maquettes/&quot;&gt;1:11 scale maquette set up and posed&lt;/a&gt;, I started work on the 1:7 scale versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step was to create the 1:7 scale armatures, then make a foam base to save clay, and then start sculpting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monster clay is just so nice to work with, and using it gives me the freedom and flexibility to edit as much as I want. The only downside is that it can’t be cured. So, my overall plan is to build out a mostly detailed model with Monster clay, and then I’ll create a mold, cast it, and chop it up into pieces to refine further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;17-scale-armatures&quot;&gt;1:7 scale armatures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to make and print 3d models of the head, ribcage, and pelvis in Blender to add to the armature. Since I’m using Monster clay, I don’t have to worry about the armature being oven safe, so I printed them on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sovol3d.com/products/sovol-sv06-best-budget-3d-printer-for-beginner&quot;&gt;SV06&lt;/a&gt; with PLA. In the end, I didn’t bother printing the heads since I’ll use a different construction method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2024-05-12-1-7-scale-sculpt/blender_pelvis_rib.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Head, ribcage, and pelvis 3D models in Blender, showing a top and 3/4 view.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Simplified head, rib, and pelvis 3D models in Blender with holes for 1/8th scale armature wire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest pain was getting the wire to stick to the PLA. I tried super glue, then switched to apoxie which did work better, but not perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was trying to figure out a simple way to get the wire for the clavicle in the right place. The loop in front solution I did for this version wasn’t great. The loop broke, and the loop placement meant I had to scale down the rib too much, which kind of defeated the point of having it as a landmark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For V2 I’ll probably just chop off the top of the ribcage so that it ends where the clavicles connect to the sternum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cutting-the-foam-base&quot;&gt;Cutting the foam base&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I didn’t have any proper crafting foam, I opted for using some scrap leftover from a package. This foam is really squishy and did not want to stick together, but it was better than nothing. Using the foam cutter is incredibly satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2024-05-12-1-7-scale-sculpt/foam_base.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A mess of foam scraps and a foam base.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Went a bit ham with the foam cutter. I collected up the scraps in a bad for future use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The armature stuck in pretty easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2024-05-12-1-7-scale-sculpt/foam_base-02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rough foam base with wire armature inserted&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Setting up the armature on the foam base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next time I try this method, I’ll spend more time figuring out the scale, and maybe keep the shapes simpler and more blocky. There’s clay going on top to form the terrain and details anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;starting-to-build&quot;&gt;Starting to build&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monster clay comes in an oven safe container, which is so cool, but my oven’s lowest heat setting is too hot for the clay. After a couple of weeks of heating the clay up with the oven door open to keep it cool enough, I just went and bought a little crockpot to keep it in. Saves me having to work in the kitchen and create a fire hazard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started by slapping on some of the basic forms for the arms, legs, torso and some of the basic musculature. I broke off a lot of this initial sculpting as I made adjustments to the poses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2024-05-12-1-7-scale-sculpt/sculpt_initial_shaping.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two armatures on a foam base with bits of clay added.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Slapped some Monster clay on to get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I covered the foam base in dollar store plasticine to keep it distinct from the figures and also to save the Monster clay. The structural integrity of the base is not great, but it’s good enough for this stage. I did a couple of quick heads with some face landmarks to help with the poses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2024-05-12-1-7-scale-sculpt/sculpt_progress.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Refined armature&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Coated the base in blue plasticine, refined and adjusted the poses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next part will be the most time intensive: refining the sculpt. It’s incredibly satisfying to work on though, I’m having a ton of fun.&lt;/p&gt;

		</content>
		
		<author>
			<name>Justin</name></author>
		<summary type="html">Getting the armatures, foam base, and initial clay pass of the 1:7 scale versions of the first figure sculpt</summary>
		<category term="posts"/>
		<category term="sculpting"/><category term="yra and urd frazetta style"/>
	</entry><entry>
		<title>Sculpting rough maquettes</title>
		<link href="http://localhost:4000/20240402_sculpting-rough-maquettes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sculpting rough maquettes"/>
		<published>2024-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</published>
		<updated>2024-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://localhost:4000/20240402_sculpting-rough-maquettes/</id>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/20240402_sculpting-rough-maquettes/">
		
  		
	&lt;p&gt;3 min.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;I really wanted to make a Frank Frazetta style sculpture of a couple of my characters Yra and Urd. I’m aiming for 1:7 scale and did the armatures but ran into a couple of snags trying to work from my sketch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first issue is that when doing mock up sketches, I always find it hard to work out how the composition will look from different angles (&lt;em&gt;part of the fun of having &lt;a href=&quot;https://aphantasia.com/what-is-aphantasia/&quot;&gt;aphantasia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second but related issue was the base. I didn’t want to use pure clay for the base (&lt;em&gt;I only have a couple of lbs of Monster Clay&lt;/em&gt;) but needed a better sense of what shape the base actually needed to be to fit the figures, especially since I need to be able to pierce into it with wire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I thought it would be easier to give myself a reference to work from and whip up a couple of 1:11 scale maquettes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;making-the-bodies&quot;&gt;Making the bodies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started by printing my turnaround ref at the right scale (&lt;em&gt;Urd’s 1:11 is much bigger than Yra’s&lt;/em&gt;), and built simple armatures with 16 gague aluminium wire. Then I added a rough rib and pelvis shape with apoxy and a thin coating around the arms, legs, and shoulders to limit the articulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the apoxy dried (&lt;em&gt;24 hours is a long wait&lt;/em&gt;), I used some Super Sculpey to built up the shapes a bit. I ended up making a bit of a mistake around the legs by not accounting for them having to bend, so after I baked them I carved out the grooves needed to get the legs to bend enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;making-the-faces-by-working-smarter-not-harder&quot;&gt;Making the faces by working smarter not harder&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still working out how to sculpt faces in that kind of flat style, and doing it at 1:11 scale was kind of not worth it for a quick mockup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, since I had some (&lt;em&gt;accidentally&lt;/em&gt;) knock-off &lt;a href=&quot;https://myfigurecollection.net/?_tb=item&amp;amp;title=Body-kun&quot;&gt;Body-kun and Body-chan&lt;/a&gt; figures that I never really used because of the limited articulation. I tore them apart and made some quick face molds with Easy Mold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I baked the initial mold then added the ears and flattened the nose bridge, baked them again, then added the head and stuck it on the wire. I had to add some apoxy afterwards because they didn’t want to stick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2024-04-02-sculpting-rough-maquettes/head_mold.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Face mold&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The adapted Body-chan face mold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sword&quot;&gt;Sword&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the sword, we had some flat wooden sticks lying around that would work pretty well for the sword shape I needed. I tried cutting out the handle but it ended up snapping since the wood was so thin, so instead I filed a groove out and used armature wire and apoxy to form a rudimentary handle and pommel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-results&quot;&gt;The results&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty happy with how they turned out, though I definitely learned some lessons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The first and biggest one is that aluminum wire is no good for something that needs to bend over and over again. Which I should have known but alas.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They each had a leg snap at the knee when I was re-carving. If I do a second set, I’ll use steel wire instead.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The sculpey and apoxy also cracked a lot around where it met the wire, and didn’t adhere very well to the wire.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The scale of the heads is too big, I’ll need to actually make a custom sculpt in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2024-04-02-sculpting-rough-maquettes/maquettes_flat.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Maquettes flatlay&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;They live! I didn’t spend too much time making them pretty but they’ll do the trick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;putting-the-maquettes-to-use&quot;&gt;Putting the maquettes to use&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly I was able to match my rough sketches pretty closely which is exciting! I took some pictures to sketch on top of for some of the additional details and where I wanted to make adjustments. I just used plasticine for the base to get a sense of the shape and scale, which was &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; different than what I was picturing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2024-04-02-sculpting-rough-maquettes/turn_around_sketch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sculpture turnaround sketch&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;My initial sketches compared to the overlay sketches from photo reference. Honestly wasn’t expecting to be able to match them that closely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;Carousel4053&quot; class=&quot;carousel slide&quot; data-ride=&quot;carousel&quot; data-interval=&quot;2000&quot;&gt;
  
  &lt;ol class=&quot;carousel-indicators&quot;&gt;
	  &lt;li data-target=&quot;#Carousel4053&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;active&quot;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	  
	  &lt;li data-target=&quot;#Carousel4053&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	  &lt;/ol&gt;	
 
  &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-inner&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-item active&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;https://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;
    
	&lt;img class=&quot;d-block mw-100 chulapa-carousel&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/img/posts/2024-04-02-sculpting-rough-maquettes/11_scale_mockup/sculpture_mockup_side.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Carousel Item #1&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-item&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;https://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;
    
	&lt;img class=&quot;d-block mw-100 chulapa-carousel&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/img/posts/2024-04-02-sculpting-rough-maquettes/11_scale_mockup/sculpture_mockup_front.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Carousel Item #2&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-control-prev&quot; href=&quot;#Carousel4053&quot; role=&quot;button&quot; data-slide=&quot;prev&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;carousel-control-prev-icon&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;sr-only&quot;&gt;Previous&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-control-next&quot; href=&quot;#Carousel4053&quot; role=&quot;button&quot; data-slide=&quot;next&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;carousel-control-next-icon&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;sr-only&quot;&gt;Next&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;It’s all coming together!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now onto the next step, building it all again in 1:7 scale.&lt;/p&gt;

		</content>
		
		<author>
			<name>Justin</name></author>
		<summary type="html">First attempt at building a small maquette as a visual aid for sculpting</summary>
		<category term="posts"/>
		<category term="sculpting"/>
	</entry><entry>
		<title>Story(teller) time</title>
		<link href="http://localhost:4000/20240206_there-are-two-wolves-inside-me/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Story(teller) time"/>
		<published>2024-02-06T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		<updated>2024-02-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>http://localhost:4000/20240206_there-are-two-wolves-inside-me/</id>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/20240206_there-are-two-wolves-inside-me/">
		
  		
	&lt;p&gt;2 min.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;I’m not much of a tradition or holiday person in general, but I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; like to start the new year by setting out goals for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2024 is the year of the dragon (&lt;em&gt;Finally my sign again🐉&lt;/em&gt;). Feels like an especially important one to make a fresh start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-bit-of-backstory&quot;&gt;A bit of backstory&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Way, way back in grade 1, the teacher had a few different activities that the kids were supposed to do each week. I don’t remember most of the activities because I only ever did one. The activity was filling out a specific notebook that the teacher provided. The notebook pages were divided into two sections: the top two-thirds of the page were blank and the bottom third had ruled lines to write on. They were usually cut into fun shapes, which just added to the fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pretty quickly monopolized those notebooks, to the point where it was addressed in some kind of parent teacher interview situation, with the teacher begging me to do something else, anything else. (&lt;em&gt;I didn’t&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-wouldnt-exactly-call-myself-an-illustrator&quot;&gt;I wouldn’t exactly call myself an illustrator&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past few years most of my output has been digital illustration, but the illustrator box I’ve been stuck in has felt increasingly suffocating. I’ve always loved drawing, but it’s never been my only love. Not even my first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Storytelling&lt;/strong&gt; has always been my true love. The more I’ve neglected to nurture the storyteller in me, the more uninspired and frustrated I’ve felt overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;creative-focus-for-2024&quot;&gt;Creative focus for 2024&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So! This year I’m going to nurture the storyteller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main creative focuses this year are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prose&lt;/strong&gt;: I’ve done &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/patron-saints&quot;&gt;a bit&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/standalone/&quot;&gt;writing&lt;/a&gt; this past year but need to work those creative writing muscles more consistently. (&lt;em&gt;I do a lot of writing at my dayjob but technical writing is a pretty different beast&lt;/em&gt;). I have a backlog of first drafts, WIPs, and outlines that I just need to sit down and dedicate time to.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game development&lt;/strong&gt;: I started learning &lt;a href=&quot;https://godotengine.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Godot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on the recommendation of a friend who is an actual proper developer. I love Twine and interactive fiction, but I also want to dive into making more game-y games.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sculpting and modeling&lt;/strong&gt;: I got back into &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blender.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blender&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; again and am having a lot of fun with it. 3D modelling really helped me realize how much I’ve missed sculpting with my hands, so I’ve been getting back into that as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the overall roadmap for now. I’ll keep drawing, but I’m sticking to drawing as &lt;strong&gt;part&lt;/strong&gt; of what I do, not the whole that defines me.&lt;/p&gt;

		</content>
		
		<author>
			<name>Justin</name></author>
		<summary type="html">There are two wolves inside of me and one of them is done being ignored.</summary>
		<category term="posts"/>
		<category term="reflections"/>
	</entry><entry>
		<title>New Year, first post</title>
		<link href="http://localhost:4000/20240204_first-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Year, first post"/>
		<published>2024-02-04T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		<updated>2024-02-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>http://localhost:4000/20240204_first-post/</id>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/20240204_first-post/">
		
  		
	&lt;p&gt;2 min.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;At the end of the year last year, I decided to take a step to regroup and figure out how to navigate my relationship with art and online spaces. I didn’t expect that reflection time to take all of 2023 and then some, but then life kept Happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt very much like Humpty Dumpty teetering atop a swiss cheese-ass lookin’ Jenga tower while some unseen malevolent force pulled out piece after piece until it all toppled down. (&lt;em&gt;Yes that metaphor is a mess, but so was life.&lt;/em&gt;) The silver lining was that lying broken on the floor doesn’t give you much else to do &lt;em&gt;except&lt;/em&gt; reflect. And I’m feeling optimistic about where I’ve landed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;creating-content&quot;&gt;“Creating Content”&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve already &lt;a href=&quot;https://wickedliltongue.tumblr.com/post/704357808625401857/art-versus-artist-2022-i-dont-usually-do-these&quot;&gt;ranted&lt;/a&gt; about how bad online spaces have been over the past couple of years, so I won’t spend too much time going over it all again. Suffice to say, it’s been hard to find any joy in making art and sharing it knowing that it’s just going to become fuel for the horrors of the Content Machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My desire to make art doesn’t come from a desire to make money; money is a necessary evil to survive. My boyfriend likes to poke fun at me for being “allergic to making money off my art”. But he’s not entirely wrong. The moment that making money becomes the primary motivation to make art is the moment I lose all interest. Making art is like breathing. It’s necessary. It’s a core part of who I am. And how can I possibly tie that down to a price tag? What’s the monetary value of each inhale and exhale?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;my-brand-is-being-chaotic&quot;&gt;My “brand” is being chaotic&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always struggled with trying to build my work around a specific niche or artistic discipline. I may barely sleep for a week doing a deep dive into say, making a &lt;a href=&quot;/games/interactive-fiction&quot;&gt;little interactive game&lt;/a&gt;, then not touch Twine for another 3 years because I’ve picked up 10 other crafts, only to decide that making games is pretty fun, and maybe I should do some more of that. Committing to a single discipline, subject, or even technique just doesn’t work for me. Especially not on a timeline, which has always made having a consistent online presence tricky. (Hello ADHD, sure was eye opening learning &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; about myself).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m not going to! I’m just going to commit to following my interests, at my own pace, and seeing where it leads me.&lt;/p&gt;

		</content>
		
		<author>
			<name>Justin</name></author>
		<summary type="html">Starting off the new year (at bit late) with the results of a year of reflection on making and sharing art.</summary>
		<category term="posts"/>
		<category term="reflections"/>
	</entry></feed>